JONATHAN T. PREDMORE

136 Cool Creek Manor Dr. Wrightsville PA (814)203-1167 jonnyedu@yahoo.com

Professional Profile

Unique combination of K-12 teaching experience coupled with fourteen years personnel management background in military logistics.

- Holds Bachelor's Science in Education and a certification from the Army Logistical University at FT Lee VA.
- Experienced in use of the Internet and educational software with the ability to manipulate Excel and PowerPoint to present lessons in multiple mediums.

Education

B.S. Education

Old Dominion University, Darden College of Education, Norfolk, VA. 1995

Commissioned Army Ordnance Officer

Army Logistical University, FT Lee VA 2010

Clearance Secret

Honors

Army Achievement Medal 2x State Service Ribbon (Flood Fight in MN) Good Conduct 2x Overseas Service Ribbon 3x Army Service Ribbon National Defense Ribbon 2x (Desert Storm and Enduring Freedom)

Provisional Certifications

VA K-12 HE/PHY Education. 1995

PA K-12 HE/PHY Education. 2001 (Reciprocal License)

Key Qualifications

Certified Teacher K-12 Educator with experience in a multitude of environs (Experienced Instructor)

Incorporates pedagogical principles into classroom, and individual instruction while developing and conducting cross-curricular activities

I am a trained military officer, possessing the flexibility to adapt to students needs

Utilizes automated and traditional methods, and can resources necessary items from available assets

Computer Skills

- **Software (IBM and MAC environments):** Microsoft Windows®, WordPerfect, Excel, Microsoft Office, PageMaker
- Knowledge of the Internet for purposes of research and instruction.
- System installations and debugging; terminal/printer operations/ Proxima projectors and Promethean boards, as well as accompanying devices

Employment

[2012-Present] [ARNG] [Elizabeth Towne Armory]

OFFICER PAARNG

- Deployed as Maintenance Control Officer
- Evaluated and ensured the quality of all services completed by the maintenance platoon.
- Developed training and cross-training plan for maintenance personnel
- Coordinated the recovery of battalion equipment in secured environment
- Deployed to Kuwait with the 228 Brigade Support Battalion in support of Operation Enduring Freedom (OEF)
- Monitor the status of equipment undergoing repairs, and determine the status of the repair
 parts required to complete those repairs
- Tracked 249 vehicles, logged man-hours and parts, calculated and reported operational readiness (O.R.) to supervisor via Excel and PowerPoint
- Planned and led convoys from Lock haven Armory to the Ft Indian Town Gap training facility Annville PA in coordination with the DOT
- Established priority of maintenance IAW battalion commander's intent
- Ensured Maximum Combat Power for the duration of deployment beginning with a 75%, ending with a 93% O.R. rate

[2011-Present] [PA Public Schools] [Potter, York, Lancaster, County's] SUBSTITUTE TEACHER

- Substitute Teacher, K 12 (Currently)
- Employed with STS (Substitute Teacher Service) Fall 2013 to Present
- On call for all subjects
- Long Term substitute for Health and Physical Education for Austin School district (Fall 2012), prior to deployment [ref. available]
- Long Term substitute for NJROTC Penn York High School five months (2014-15 school year) [ref. available]
- Created instructional resources for use in the classroom.
- Met course and school-wide student performance goals
- Created lesson plans and modified accordingly

[2006-2011] [Camp Ripley] [Little Falls MN]

OFFICER MN ARNG

- Coordinated and led training for gunners and mechanics
- Assigned responsibilities of the Maintenance Control Officer & Maintenance Platoon Leader, in the absence of a second officer (see above description)
- Performed the duties of Senior Rater for all NCOs and lower Enlisted soldiers in my platoon
- Maintain personal fitness level in accordance with Army policy

[2004-2006] [SBC] [Bozeman Montana]

Timber and Stick Framer

- Assisted in the building of timber framed homes using a myriad of different tools such as, chainsaws, chisels, and an assortment of other power and hand tools.
- Worked as a stick framer for the same company using more traditional carpentry tools
- Framed, hung rafters, built and placed knee braces, and hung windows and doors
- I have been licensed on all lift equipment (GEHL, Genie, etc...) as well as forklifts and skidsteers
- Educated on reading plans and transferring scale to wood stock
- · Adept at towing and backing with gooseneck trailers
- Knowledgeable and practiced in the use of overhead cranes (both indoor and outdoor)

[2002-2004] Adelphia Children's Home Westfield PA]

Health and Physical Education Teacher and Counselor

- Taught Health Physical Education, Math, and Current Events
- Counseled Emotionally Disturbed, MR students in a children's home
- · Administered medications to children and maintained accountability
- Trained and certified in child restraint protocols
- Created instructional resources for use in the classroom.
- Met course and school-wide student performance goals
- Created lesson plans and modified accordingly

[1998-2001] [Edgar Allen Poe Middle School]

Health and Physical Education Teacher

- Created and implemented Health and Physical education curriculum
- Maintained a classroom of 40 plus children in multiple activities
- Maintained and improved knowledge of child psychology, and biomechanics through research and implementation
- Used Polar Heart Rate monitors in all PE classes to mitigate possible stress related injuries
- · Team taught with special education teacher when necessary

[1995-1998] [Fairfax County Public Schools VA]

Substitute Teacher and Personal Trainer

- Substitute taught in the Fairfax County public school system
- Personal Trained (Skyline Clubs: Crystal Gateway, Gold's Gym: Clarington)

[1986-1990] [US Army Active Duty] [Stateside and OCONUS tours]

Active Army / Calvary Scout

- Reconnaissance Scout
- Track and Wheeled vehicle operator
- Attended multiple major field missions (California, Korea and Germany)
- Proficient with all crew serve weapons and individual weapons
- Patrolled the Demilitarized Zone during a Korea tour
- Proficient in Land Navigation (Orienteering, GPS, Compass)